National Organization of Women, Connecticut Chapter Records 1996.0014
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
National Organization for Women, Connecticut Chapter Records
Bulk, 1970-2004
undated, 1939, 1964-2004
1996.0014
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
115.0 Linear feet
The collection contains the administrative records of the Connecticut Chapter of the National Organization for Women. CT NOW believes that the personal is indeed political; therefore it strives to impact and change attitudes, beliefs, and policies that harm all women by fighting for political, economic, and social justice through education, organizing and action.
History
The National Organization for Women is the largest organization of feminist activists in the United States. NOW has more than 500,000 contributing members and more than 500 local and campus affiliates in all 50 states and the District of Columbia. Since our founding in 1966, NOW's goal has been "to take action" to bring about equality for all women. Both the actions NOW takes and its position on the issues are principled, uncompromising and often ahead of their time.
Detailed information about the history and activities of the organization is available on the NOW website.
CT NOW believes that the personal is indeed political; therefore it strives to impact and change attitudes, beliefs, and policies that harm all women by fighting for political, economic, and social justice through education, organizing and action. This purpose includes, but is not limited to, equal rights and responsibilities in all aspects of citizenship, public service, employment, education, family life, and it includes freedom from discrimination because of race, gender or perceived gender, ethnicity, origin, age, marital status, sexual preference/orientation, physical ability/health status, or parenthood.
Information about the Connecticut Chapter is available on their website.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the documentation of the programs, activities and administration of the Connecticut Chapter of the National Organization for Women.
Provenance and Acquisition
The collection has been transferred by the Chapter in installments beginning in 1996.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut based organizations and politics. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
National Organization for Women. Connecticut Chapter.; National Organization for Women. Connecticut Chapter.; Administrative records.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Organizational records; Photographs.; Publications.; Video Recordings.
- Series I: Inventory, Bulk, 1970-2004; undated, 1939, 1964-2004
  - Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, 1983-1994 (Box 1, Box MI_1)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Subjects include: NOW minutes, papers, letters to legislation.]
  - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Financial Records, 1991-1998 (Box 2)
    [Subjects include: Legislative correspondence, chapter dues.]
  - Fliers, Newspaper Clippings, Administrative and Financial Records, Publications, Correspondence, 1986-1995 (Box 3)
    [Subjects include: Activists, National NOW Times, membership itinerary, women’s suffrage.]
  - 1993-1995 (Box 4)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Publications, Notes, Correspondence [Subjects inlcude: NOW dues, CT NOW meetings, finances.]
  - 1993 (Box 5)
    Realia, Photos, Video Recordings (4 VHS)[Subjects include: NOW training, stamps, pin, (2) canvas bags, (10) t-shirts.]
  - 1995-2001 (Box 6)
    Awards, Publications, Fliers, Correspondence, Notes, Newspaper Clippings, Financial Records[Subjects include: 13th Annual Feminist Awards Dinner “Year of the Women.”]
  - Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, 1995 (Box 7)
    [Subjects include: Women’s Rights.]
  - Administrative Records, Correspondences, Newspaper Clippings, Publications, 1990-1994 (Box 8)
    [Subjects include: Policy manuals.]
  - Manuscript, Newspaper Clippings, (2) data disks, Administrative Records, Publications, Realia, 1989-1992 (Box 9)
    [Subjects include: CT NOW minutes, pro-choice, stop domestic violence pin.]
  - Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, Administrative and Financial Records, Publications, 1983-1989 (Box 10)
    [Subjects include: Banner, NOW minutes and Annual Reports, NOW correspondence.]
  - Notes, Publications, Administrative Records, Publication, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, 1984-1989 (Box 11)
    [Subjects include: Fundraising, New Leadership in the Public Interest, National Assembly of the Future of the Family, NOW Records, Farmington Valley News.]
  - 1975-1992 (Box 12)
    Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Administrative Records, Correspondence [Subjects include: Pro-choice Rally, NOW correspondence, Domestic Violence against Women, War, Peace and Women.]
  - 1978-1997 (Box 13)
    Photographs, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Administrative and Financial Records [Subjects include: Promise Keepers, NOW chapter dues, NOW meetings and state conventions.]
  - 1989-1999 (Box 14)
    Newspaper Clippings, Administrative Records, Fliers, Manuscripts, Notes [Subjects include: Pro-choice Rally, NOW chapter Newsletters.]
  - Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings, Manuscripts, Correspondence, Publication, 1988-1991 (Box 15)
    [Subjects include: Pro-choice Rally, Project “Stand up for Women.”]
  - Notes, Fliers, Newspaper Clippings, Manuscripts, Correspondence, Publication, Financial Records, 1979-1989 (Box 16)
    [Subjects include: Pro-choice vs. Pro-life, Coalition for Women in Prison, Planned Parenthood Insurance and NOW policy.]
  - Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings, Manuscripts, Fliers, Publications, Financial Records, Correspondence, 1989-1993 (Box 17)
    [Subjects include: NOW Rally, meeting minutes, CT News.]
  - Publication, Administrative Records, Correspondence, Notes, Newspaper Clippings, 1989-1991 (Box 18)
    [Subjects include: NOW chapter newsletters, CT NOW administrative files.]
  - Manuscript, Administrative Records, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, Publications, 1973-1993 (Box 19)
    [Subjects include: Conducting a Rally, NOW bylaws, Gray Panthers.]
  - 1988-1990 (Box 20)
    Administrative Records, Manuscripts, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Financial Records, Publications [Subjects include: Bylaws, Planned Parenthood information, NOW minutes, letters to legislation, National NOW Times, NOW state and local.]
  - 1973-1991 (Box 21)
    Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Notes [Subjects include: Women’s Center Newsletter, Feminist Review, notes on women’s liberation.]
  - 2000 (Box 22)
    Realia, Visual and Audio Recordings, Newspaper Clippings, Publications [Subjects include: Pins, Stickers, (1) hat, film strips, (4) audio cassettes, (1) VHS ( United Farm Workers of America, The Wrath of Grapes), bumper stickers, license plate, bandana, “Sister” Feminine Publication.]
  - 1978-1987 (Box 33)
    Publication, Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, Correspondence, Administrative Records, Manuscripts, Notes [Subjects include: Sexual Assault, Teen Pregnancy, Legislative Committee, Pay Equity.]
  - 1987-1990 (Box 23)
    Correspondence, Administrative Records, Publication, Newspaper Clippings [Subjects include: Legislation and Teenage Pregnancy, Ladyslipper Catalogue.]
  - 1996-2002 (Box 24)
    Administrative Records, Fliers, Publications, Manuscript, Print materials [Subjects include: The Rules of the Game, Nineteenth Annual Connecticut Lobbying Conference, ConnSacs orientation manual.]
  - 1982-1989 (Box 25)
    Administrative Records, Notes, Publications, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondences, Fliers [Subject includes: Archival CT, CT NOW Papers.]
  - 1980-1989 (Box 26)
    Correspondence, Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings [Subjects include: Women’s Rights, Protests.]
  - 1970-1994 (Box 27)
    Publication, Newsletters, Correspondence, Fliers, Book, Administrative and Financial Records [Subjects include: The Waterfall, CT NOW News, NOW correspondence, Connecticut Focus.]
  - 1981-1991 (Box 28)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Manuscripts, Correspondence, Publication, Newspaper Clippings, Legal Documents, Publication [Subjects include: Federal Legislation, meeting minutes, National Times.]
  - 1983-2000 (Box 29)
    Manuscript, Notes, Administrative Records, Publication, Fliers, Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, Legal Documents [Subjects include: Court Documents, Economy Equity Act, CT NOW Lesbian Rights.]
  - 1980-1984 (Box 30)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Correspondence, Fliers [Subjects include: Executive Committee List, CT NOW By-Laws, Insurance, Supreme Court.]
  - 1982 (Box 31)
    Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Fliers [Subjects include: Reproductive Rights, NOW Times.]
  - 1978-1991 (Box 32)
    Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Fliers, Legal Documents, Administrative Records, Notes [Subjects include: National Organization for Women Newspaper, NOW jobs.]
  - 1988-1991 (Box 34)
    Correspondence, Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings, Audio Recordings, Photographs, Publication [Subjects include: Facts on Reproductive Rights, Annual Report, Empowering Women NOW, (12) Audio tapes.]
  - 1982-1990 (Box 35)
    Publication, Fliers, Notes, Administrative and Financial Records, Correspondence [Subjects include: Women’s Equality, Women’s Rights, CT NOW fundraising committee.]
  - 1981-1988 (Box 36)
    Newspaper Clippings, Administrative and Financial Records, Fliers, Manuscripts, Notes [Subjects include: The Waterfall Connecticut News, NOW Times, Fundraising.]
  - 1978-1994 (Box 37)
    Newspaper Clippings, Publication, Administrative and Financial Records, Correspondence, Manuscript [Subjects include: Informed Consent for Abortion Legislation Committee, TASC, Pro-Choice.]
  - 1989-1993 (Box 38)
    Notes, Administrative Records, Calendar, Fliers, Publications, Manuscripts, Newspaper Clippings [Subjects include: Women’s Equality, NOW Bylaws, The Politics of Women’s Health, 21st Century Feminist Fund.]
  - 1988-1995 (Box 39)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Notes, Manuscripts, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings [Subjects include: CT NOW member survey, CT NOW records.]
  - 1992-1995 (Box 42)
    Correspondence, Legal Documents, Administrative and Financial Records, Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Fliers [Subjects include: CT News ( The Waterfall), Rally’s, CT NOW correspondence, Annual Award Ceremonies.]
  - 1988-1996 (Box 44)
    Administrative Records, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Fliers [Subjects include: CT NOW, membership questionnaire.]
  - 1989 (Box 45)
    Administrative Records, Manuscripts, Correspondence, Map, Newspaper Clippings, Poster [Subjects include: GNH NOW Questionnaire, Map/Street listing, CT NOW.]
  - 1987-1992 (Box 46)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Publication, Legal Documents [Subjects include: Congress, State and House Senate Districts, NOW PAC manual, Primaries and Caucuses.]
  - 1983-2001 (Box 47)
    Correspondence, Administrative and Financial Records, Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Manuscripts, Post Cards [Subjects include: NOW Newsletters, Surveys, Legislative meetings, Feminism.]
  - 1999-2001 (Box 48)
    Visual Recordings, Realia, Poster, Legal Documents, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, Correspondence, Administrative Records, Publications [Subjects include: (2) Sashes, (2) VHS’s, “Redefining Liberation.”]
  - 1972-1978 (Box 49)
    Publication, Fliers, Books [Subjects include: Ms. Magazine, I’m Like Me, Sisterhood is Powerful.]
  - 1973-2011 (Box 50)
    Fliers, Realia, Correspondence, Publications, Post Cards, Newspaper Clippings, Books, Award, Administrative Records [Subjects include: Bumper Sticker, (1) Pen, NOW conferences, Scrapbook, The New Woman’s Survival Guide.]
  - undated (Box 51)
    Fliers, Newspaper Clippings, Administrative Records [Subjects include: PCSW News, Abortion, National NOW Times, The Waterfall CT NOW News.]
  - 1980-1993 (Box 52)
    Photographs, Realia, Poster, Audio Recordings, Fliers, Correspondence, Notes, Administrative Records, Publications, Manuscripts, Newspaper Clippings [Subjects include: (2) T-shirts, “Insurance Workshop” Audio Cassette, CT NOW Rally pins, Bumper Stickers, Name Tag ( NOW Conference), Teen mothers, CT NOW.]
  - 1975-1990 (Box 53)
    Newspapers [Subjects include: CT NOW The Waterfall.]
  - 1985-1986 (Box 54)
    Dummies[Subjects include: The Waterfall dummies.]
  - 1986-1990 (Box 55)
    Newspaper Clippings, Dummies [Subjects include: The Waterfall CT NOW News, CT NOW dummies.]
  - 1989-1995 (Box 56)
    Correspondence, Administrative Records, Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, Publications, Fliers [Subjects include: Gender Equity and Education, Restrictions, Rallies.]
  - 1990-1995 (Box 57)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Correspondence, Notes, Manuscripts, Fliers [Subjects include: Women’s Reproductive and Gay/Lesbian Rights.]
  - 1986-1999 (Box 58)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Publications, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers [Subjects include: Commerce, Legislature, Insurance, Rights and Issues.]
  - 1964-1999 (Box 59)
    Newspaper Clippings, Administrative and Financial Records, Publications, Notes, Correspondence, Fliers, Transcripts [Subjects include: CT NOW Plans.]
  - 1997-1998 (Box 61)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Fliers, Notes, Manuscripts [Subjects include: Welfare, Wage Rates, Regulations and Legislation.]
  - 1987-1997 (Box 62)
    Administrative Records, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, Correspondence, Notes [Subjects include: Promise Keepers, CT NOW Functions.]
  - 1997 (Box 63)
    Fliers, Newspaper Clippings, Administrative and Financial Records, Correspondence, Visual Recording [Subjects include: NOW CT Records, (1) VHS.]
  - 1982-1996 (Box 64)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Notes, Correspondence, Newspaper Clippings, Publication, Fliers, Legal Documents [Subjects include: The Waterfall ( CT NOW News), State Reports, Demonstrations.]
  - 1992-1995 (Box 65)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Correspondence, Publications, Fliers, Legal Documents [Subjects include: NOW CT Records.]
  - 1978-1998 (Box 66)
    Newspaper Clippings, Publication, Administrative Records [Subjects include: Women’s Rights, Annual Reports.]
  - 1988-1997 (Box 67)
    Realia, Newspaper Clippings, Awards, Photos, Visual Recordings [Subjects include: (2) VHS’s, (1) CT DBF Membership disk, (4) Greater New Haven NOW Pins, Women’s Rights.]
  - 1985-1998 (Box 68)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Newspaper Clippings, Fliers, Notes, Publications [Subjects include: CT NOW Meeting Minutes, Fundraising, Chapter Information.]
  - 1989-1996 (Box 69)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Legal Documents, Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Fliers [Subjects include: The Waterfall CT NOW News, National CT NOW Times.]
  - 1992-2005 (Box 70)
    Photographs, Visual Recording, Correspondence, Newsletter, Publications, Manuscripts, Financial Records [Subjects include: (1) DVD, Greater New Haven NOW Newsletter, National NOW Times, Family Violence, Ms. magazine.]
  - 1939-1984 (Box 71)
    Books [Subjects include: Proceedings, Extension Committee on Organization and Policy.]
  - 2002-2004 (Box 73)
    Legal Documents, Administrative and Financial Records, Magazine Clippings [Subjects include: Campaign Reform, Women’s Law Clinic, Women’s Studies.]
  - 2000-2004 (Box 74)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Correspondence, Notes, Publications, Newspaper Clippings [Subjects include: Family Issues, NOW Women’s Rights.]
  - 2000-2004 (Box 75)
    Administrative Records, Notes, Correspondence, Publications, Legal Documents [Subjects include: Women’s Rights, NOW Correspondence, Court Ruling.]
  - 1994-2005 (Box 76)
    Realia, Awards, Publications, Administrative Records [Subjects include: (1) Frisbee, (1) Mug, (1) Tote Bag, (2) T-Shirts, (1) Magnet, Pins, Bumper Stickers.]
  - 1999-2002 (Box 77)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Notes, Correspondence, Publications, Newspaper Clippings, Photographs, Visual Recordings [Subjects include: Information on Social Security, State Budget, Supreme Court, (3) DVDs.]
  - 1997-2005 (Box 78)
    Administrative and Financial Records, Correspondence, Publications [Subjects include: Unemployment, Fundraising, Women’s Career Advancement, Activism, Comprehensive Administrative Manual.]
  - 2001 (Box 79)
    Publications, Administrative Records, Manuscripts [Subjects include: Campaign Workbook.]
  - undated (Box 80)
    Realia [Subjects include: (1) Banner.]
  - undated (Box 81)
    Realia [Subjects include: (2) Banners.]
  - Clippings, Correspondence, Fliers, Publications, 1971-1972 (Box 82)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Western Connecticut chapter, Wilma Scott Heide.]
  - Realia, Flyer, Photos, Poster, Newspaper Clippings, 1989 (Oversize OS_1)
    [Subjects include: Women’s March for Equality.]
  - Award, Posters, Newspaper Clippings, 1991-1992 (Oversize OS_2)
    [Subjects include: Women’s Independence Day.]